When looking at variables over time or
عند التركيز على المتغيرات بمرور الوقت،
comparing two quantitative variables to each other,
أو مقارنة متغيرين كمّيين ببعضهما البعض،
the choices we use to visualize these cases are standardized to
تكون الخيارات التي نستخدمها لتصور هذه الحالات موحدة
the line plot and the scatter plot we saw in the previous concepts.
على معيار رسم خط المسار والمخطط المبعثر اللذين رأيناهما في المفاهيم السابقة.
However, when we introduce categorical variables into our visualization,
رغم ذلك، عندما نقدم متغيرات مطلقة إلى عرضنا المرئي
many more options now become available.
تصبح خيارات أكثر بكثير متاحة الآن.
And how to visualize the relationships between
وكيف نتصور العلاقات
categorical variables as well as with a categorical and a quantitative variable?
بين المتغيرات من جهة والمتغيرات المطلقة والكمّية من جهة أخرى؟
For example, if I want to compare two categorical variables with one another,
مثلًا، إذا أردتُ مقارنة متغيرين مطلقين ببعضهما البعض
we would probably use something like a side by side bar chart,
فربما نستخدم شيئًا كمخطط شريطي متعدد،
which shows the grouping for one category.
والذي يعرض التصنيف لفئة واحدة.
This case, chocolate, vanilla and strawberry are grouped in color for the other variable,
في هذه الحالة، يتم تصنيف الشوكولاتة والفانيليا والفراولة حسب اللون للمتغير الآخر -
the three locations in this case.
وهو المواقع الثلاثة في هذه الحالة.
We can quickly identify the favorite flavor in each location.
يمكننا تحديد المذاق المفضل في كل موضع بسرعة.
If we have more than two variables,
إذا وُجد لديكم أكثر من متغيرين -
say we wanted to view sales over time for different products,
لنقُل أننا أردنا عرض المبيعات بمرور الوقت لمنتجات مختلفة،
here we have three variables: sales, time and products.
فلدينا هنا ثلاث متغيرات: المبيعات والوقت والمنتجات.
We might start with a line chart since we're dealing with time.
قد نبدأ بمخطط خطي طالما أننا نتعامل مع الوقت،
Then, we could break out each product into its own line.
ثم يمكننا تقسيم كل منتج في السطر الخاص به.
Color the line and add a legend to provide the product name.
أضيفوا لون للسطر وأضيفوا وسيلة إيضاح لتوفير اسم المنتج.
Now we can see which products are performing well and this can help us make
يمكننا الآن أن نرى أيّ المنتجات تحقق مبيعات جيدة، وهذا قد يساعدنا
more product specific decisions than if we just looked at aggregately sales.
في اتخاذ قرارات أكثر خصوصية للمنتج مما إذا كنا قد ركَّزنا على إجمالي المبيعات فحسب.
We might instead use a stacked line chart for the situation.
يمكننا، بدلًا من ذلك، أن نستخدم مخططًا خطيًا مُكدَّسًا للموقف.
The visual provides essentially the same information but
يوفر التصور نفس المعلومات بالأساس؛
each product is shown in terms of proportion of the total sales.
لكن يُعرَض كل منتج من حيث نسبة المبيعات الكلية.
Another alternative could be to use a stack bar chart by year.
هناك بديل آخر ممكن، وهو استخدام مخطط شريطي مُكدَّس وفقًا للعام.
Each product has a color in the bar and the height of the bar is the amount of sales.
لكل منتج لون في الشرط، وارتفاع الشريط يعبر عن كمّ المبيعات.
Is one of these approaches better than another?
أيكون أحد هذه الاتجاهات أفضل من الآخر؟
I guess it depends on who you ask.
أظن أنه هذا يعتمد على من تسألون.
In the upcoming concepts,
في المفاهيم التالية،
you will see how visual encodings influenced the way we interpret
سترون كيف أثَّرت الترميزات المرئية على الطريقة التي نترجم بها المعلومات،
information and in turn how well we can draw insights from the data.
ومن ثم إلى أيّ درجة يمكننا رسم رؤى من البيانات.